Register of the Friedrich A. von Hayek papers
Hoover Institution Archives
- Incremental Materials I, 1922-2003
  - Photographs II, 1931-1934
    31 prints and reproductions depicting Martha Stefanie Braun, Francis Ysidro Edgeworth, Luigi Einaudi, Ernst Mach, Alfred Marshall, Ludwig von Mises, Roger Randerson, P. N. Rosenstein-Rodan, James Steuart, Friedrich von Wieser, and others. Includes a print depicting Carl Menger's signature.
    - 2 prints depicting unidentified group (including Ludwig Wittgenstein?), undated (Box-folder 117: 1)
    - 11 reproductions depicting various economists, including Francis Ysidro Edgeworth, Alfred Marshall, and James Steuart (Box-folder 117: 2)
    - 2 reproductions depicting Ernst Mach, undated (Box-folder 117: 3)
    - 2 prints depicting a manuscript with Carl Menger's signature, undated (Box-folder 117: 4)
    - 3 prints depicting Ludwig von Mises, undated (Box-folder 117: 5)
    - 1 print depicting Roger Randerson, undated (Box-folder 117: 6)
    - 1 print and 3 reproductions depicting Friedrich von Wieser, undated (Box-folder 117: 7)
    - 1 print depicting Martha Stefanie Braun, 1931 (Box-folder 117: 8)
    - 5 prints depicting Luigi Einaudi, P. N. Rosenstein-Rodan, and others, 1932-1934 (Box-folder 117: 9)
  - Sound Recordings I, 1977-1983
    1 sound cassette and 1 microcassette of speeches by Hayek.
    - Sound recording of an address by Hayek, Institute of Humane Studies, Menlo Park, California, 1977 June 10 (Reading room workstation)
      Use copy reference number: 86002_a_0003732
      Box/Folder 117: 10. Hayek reflects on the difficulty of educating intellectuals (the "irresponsible ignorant intellectual") on the free enterprise system. Intellectuals, Hayek argues, maintain an outmoded moral view that is incompatible with, and ultimately destructive to, a modern market economy. 1 cassette.
      A more complete copy of this session is available in the Institute for Humane Studies miscellaneous records at the Hoover Archives. That copy (86002_a_0003731) also features the remarks of other speakers at the session who refer to Hayek.
    - Sound recording of a speech by Hayek, "Evolution and Spontaneous Order," Lindau, Germany, 1983 June 28 (Reading room workstation)
      Use copy reference number: 86002_a_0003734
      Box/Folder 117: 11. 1 microcassette (partially erased).
  - Card File I, undated (Box 118)
    Miscellaneous notes, unsorted.
- Incremental Materials II, 1911-2005
  The following papers comprise the second of four sections of incremental materials of the Friedrich A. von Hayek papers. The materials were received after Hayek's death from his family and his longtime secretary, Charlotte Cubitt.
  - Biographical File III, 1911-2004
    Account, address books, articles and clippings, autobiographical fragments and statement, bibliographies, datebooks, driver's license, list of books, oral history, passports, printed materials, programs, and prospectus, arranged by physical form.
    - Account of recovery from illness, 1961 June 11 (Box-folder 119: 1)
    - Address books, 1920-1980 (Box-folder 119: 2)
    - Articles and clippings, 1927-2004
      - 1927-1964 (Box-folder 119: 3)
      - 1970-1975 (Box-folder 119: 4)
      - 1976-1977 (Box-folder 119: 5)
      - 1978-1979 (Box-folder 119: 6)
      - 1980-1982 (Box-folder 119: 7)
      - 1983 (Box-folder 119: 8)
      - 1984 (Box-folder 119: 9-10)
      - 1985 (Box-folder 119: 11)
      - 1985 (Box-folder 120: 1)
      - 1986 (Box-folder 120: 2-3)
      - 1987 (Box-folder 120: 4)
      - 1988 (Box-folder 120: 5)
      - 1989 (Box-folder 120: 6)
      - 1994-2004 (Box-folder 120: 7)
    - "Autobiographical fragments,", 1945-1967
      - 1945-1961 (Box-folder 120: 8)
      - 1967 (Box-folder 120: 9-10)
    - Autobiographical statement, 1970 June 10 (Box-folder 120: 11)
    - Bibliographies, 1980-1989
      - 1980 (Box-folder 120: 12)
      - 1988 (Box-folder 120: 13)
      - 1989 (Box-folder 120: 14)
    - Datebooks, 1911-1990
      - 1911-1913 (Box-folder 121: 1)
      - 1914-1915 (Box-folder 121: 2)
      - 1917-1918 (Box-folder 121: 3)
      - 1920-1923 (Box-folder 121: 4)
      - 1928-1931 (Box-folder 121: 5)
      - 1932-1934 (Box-folder 121: 6)
      - 1934-1936 (Box-folder 121: 7)
      - 1937-1939 (Box-folder 121: 8)
      - 1940-1941 (Box-folder 122: 1)
      - 1941-1942 (Box-folder 122: 2)
      - 1943-1945 (Box-folder 122: 3)
      - 1946-1948 (Box-folder 122: 4)
      - 1949-1952 (Box-folder 122: 5)
      - 1953-1956 (Box-folder 122: 6)
      - 1956-1958 (Box-folder 122: 7)
      - 1959-1961 (Box-folder 122: 8)
      - 1962-1964 (Box-folder 122: 9)
      - 1965-1967 (Box-folder 123: 1)
      - 1968-1970 (Box-folder 123: 2)
      - 1971-1973 (Box-folder 123: 3)
      - 1974-1975 (Box-folder 123: 4)
      - 1977-1979 (Box-folder 123: 5)
      - 1980-1982 (Box-folder 123: 6)
      - 1983-1985 (Box-folder 123: 7)
      - 1986-1988 (Box-folder 123: 8)
      - 1989-1990 (Box-folder 123: 9)
    - Driver's license, 1930 (Box-folder 123: 10)
    - List of books sold to the Bank for International Settlements, 1939 (Box-folder 123: 11)
    - Oral history, 1983 (Box-folder 124: 1)
      Interviews conducted by Armen A. Alchian, Robert Bork, James Buchanan, Robert Chitester, Earlene Craver, Jack High, Axel Leijonhufvud, and Leo Rosten under the auspices of the Oral History Program, University of California at Los Angeles.
    - Passports, 1919-1986 (Box-folder 124: 2)
    - Printed materials accompanying the video series, "Hayek-Freedom's Philosopher,", 1995 (Box-folder 124: 3)
    - Programs for ceremonies and events in honor of Hayek, 1979-1992 (Box-folder 124: 4)
    - Prospectus for the publication of Hayek's collected works, 1985 (Box-folder 124: 5-6)
    - Reading list, 1918-1922 (Box-folder 125: 1)
    - Travel journal, 1954-1955 (Box-folder 125: 2)
  - Correspondence III, 1912-1991
    Letters, cards, and enclosures, arranged alphabetically by name of correspondent.
    - General, 1978-1989
      - Birthday greetings, 1989 (Box-folder 125: 5-6)
      - "Paris Challenge" correspondence, 1978
        - Circular letters, 1978 (Box-folder 125: 7)
        - Lists of addressees, 1978 (Box-folder 125: 8)
        - Replies, 1978
          - A-K, 1978 (Box-folder 125: 9)
          - L-W, 1978 (Box-folder 125: 10)
    - Unidentified, 1914-1983 (Box-folder 125: 11)
      Folder contains letters from Erich Hayek and Erick von Kuehnelt-Leddin.
    - American Economic Association (Teresa Kennedy), 1979 (Box-folder 125: 12)
    - Aims of Industry (Michael Ivens), 1983 (Box-folder 125: 13)
    - Aomi, Junichi, 1996 (Box-folder 125: 14)
    - Bartley, William W., 1962-1990
      - 1962-1982 (Box-folder 125: 15)
      - 1983 (Box-folder 125: 16)
      - 1984 (Box-folder 126: 1)
      - 1985 (Box-folder 126: 2)
      - 1986 (Box-folder 126: 3)
      - 1987 (Box-folder 126: 4)
      - 1988 (Box-folder 126: 5)
      - 1989-1990 (Box-folder 126: 6)
    - Basil Blackwell Publishers (David Martin), 1982 (Box-folder 126: 7)
    - Bellow, Saul, 1979 (Box-folder 126: 8)
    - Bosch, Alfred, 1978 (Box-folder 126: 9)
    - Braun, Conrad J., 1980 (Box-folder 126: 10)
    - Broadley, James, 1982 (Box-folder 126: 11)
    - Cato Institute (Edward H. Crane, Robert Formaini, George H. Pearson), 1977-1980 (Box-folder 126: 12)
    - Center for the Criticism of Ideas (John A. Clinchy), 1980 (Box-folder 126: 13)
    - Council for a Competitive Economy (Joe Cobb), 1981 (Box-folder 126: 14)
    - Cubitt, Charlotte, 1977-1990
      - 1977-1980 (Box-folder 126: 15)
      - 1981-1983 (Box-folder 126: 16)
      - 1984-1990 (Box-folder 126: 17)
    - Donner, Neal, 1986 (Box-folder 126: 18)
    - Drexler, K. Eric, 1986 (Box-folder 126: 19)
    - Economica (Irene Anderson, M. H. Miller, Ray Richardson), 1974-1975 (Box-folder 126: 20)
    - Eucken, Walter, 1947-1949 (Box-folder 126: 21)
    - Filbinger, Hans, 1975-1982 (Box-folder 126: 22)
    - Forbes (Ronald Bailey), 1989 (Box-folder 126: 23)
    - Frankfürter Allgemeine Zeitung, 1979-1983 (Box-folder 126: 24)
    - Frickhöffer, Wolfgang, 1978 (Box-folder 126: 25)
    - Fürth, J. Herbert, 1985-1990 (Box-folder 127: 1)
    - Garrett, Andrew, 1980 (Box-folder 127: 2)
    - Geers, Volker J., 1989 (Box-folder 127: 3)
    - Graham, Gerald S., 1978 (Box-folder 127: 4)
    - Harris, Ralph, 1990 (Box-folder 127: 5)
    - Hartwell, Max, 1986 (Box-folder 127: 6)
    - Hayek, August von, 1912-1922 (Box-folder 127: 7)
    - Hayek, Erich and Edith, 1950-1963 (Box-folder 127: 8)
    - Hennings, K. H., 1984-1985 (Box-folder 127: 9)
    - Hepworth, Brian, 1986 (Box-folder 127: 10)
    - Hofe, Renate vom, 1986 (Box-folder 127: 11)
    - Hoover Institution (Charles Palm, John Raisian), 1990 (Box-folder 127: 12)
    - Hoppmann, Erich, 1975-1985 (Box-folder 127: 13)
    - Hückel, Fritz A., 1985 (Box-folder 127: 14)
    - Hunold, Maximiliane, 1980 (Box-folder 127: 15)
    - Instituto Liberal (José Italo Stelle), 1983 (Box-folder 127: 16)
    - Kratky, Otto, 1979-1980 (Box-folder 127: 17)
    - Kresge, Stephen, 1990-1991 (Box-folder 127: 18)
    - Lagler, Ernst, 1975 (Box-folder 127: 19)
    - Lasky, Melvin J., 1977 (Box-folder 127: 20)
    - Lepage, Henri, 1979 (Box-folder 127: 21)
    - Liberty Fund (A. N. McLeod), 1975-1985 (Box-folder 127: 22)
    - London School of Economics (Alexander Carr-Saunders), 1950 (Box-folder 127: 23)
    - Luhnow, Harold W., 1948-1950 (Box-folder 127: 24)
    - Machan, Tibor R., 1979 (Box-folder 127: 25)
    - Machlup, Fritz, 1938 (Box-folder 127: 26)
    - McCloughry, Roy K., 1982 (Box-folder 127: 27)
    - Mellanby, Kenneth, 1991 (Box-folder 127: 28)
    - Miller, Loren B., 1947 (Box-folder 127: 29)
    - Morris, Walter, 1990 (Box-folder 127: 30)
    - Nishiyama, Chiaki, 1986 (Box-folder 127: 31)
    - Olive, Vivienne, 1977 (Box-folder 127: 32)
    - Pearson, George H., 1976-1977 (Box-folder 127: 33)
    - Philosophia Verlag (Hilla Hueber), 1986 (Box-folder 127: 34)
    - Ren, Youlin, 1984 (Box-folder 127: 35)
    - Routledge and Keegan, Ltd. (Clare Alexander, Alison Barr, Elizabeth Fidlon, Norman Franklin, Peter Sowden), 1977-1990 (Box-folder 127: 36)
    - Rueff, Jacques, 1978 (Box-folder 127: 37)
    - Samuelson, Paul A., 1980-1981 (Box-folder 127: 38)
    - Skrbensky, Otto, 1946 (Box-folder 127: 39)
    - Spearman, Diane, 1984 (Box-folder 127: 40)
    - Stallner, Johann, 1952-1953 (Box-folder 127: 41)
    - Tebbit Norman, 1981 (Box-folder 127: 42)
    - Thatcher, Margaret, 1979-1984 (Box-folder 127: 43)
    - University of Chicago Press, 1983-1990 (Box-folder 127: 44)
    - Van Harlingen, Laurette, 1952-1954 (Box-folder 127: 45)
    - Wieber, J. F., 1976 (Box-folder 127: 46)
    - World Wildlife Fund (Fritz Vollmar), 1976 (Box-folder 127: 47)
  - Charlotte Cubitt Correspondence File, 1977-2000
    Letters and enclosures, arranged alphabetically by name of correspondent.
    - Unidentified, 1997 (Box-folder 127: 48)
      Folder contains a letter from Lanny Ebenstein.
    - Arnolds, Rolf, 1983 (Box-folder 127: 49)
    - Bartley, William W., 1982-1988
      - 1982-1985 (Box-folder 127: 50)
      - 1986-1988 (Box-folder 127: 51)
    - Cato Institute (Edward H. Crane), 1992 (Box-folder 127: 52)
    - Crowley, Brian Lee, 1989-1991 (Box-folder 127: 53)
    - Fisher, Antony G. A., 1986 (Box-folder 128: 1)
    - Fürth, J. Herbert, 1985-1992 (Box-folder 128: 2)
    - Harris, Ralph, 1990-1992 (Box-folder 128: 3)
    - Hartwell, Max, 1986 (Box-folder 128: 4)
    - Hayek, Friedrich A. von, 1977-1987 (Box-folder 128: 5)
    - Heritage Foundation (Ewin J. Feulner, Jr.), 1992 (Box-folder 128: 6)
    - Hoover Institution (John Raisian), 1991-1992 (Box-folder 128: 7)
    - Horváth, T., 1991-1992 (Box-folder 128: 8)
    - Institute for Humane Studies (William W. Beach), 1992 (Box-folder 128: 9)
    - Kresge, Stephen, 1990-1992 (Box-folder 128: 10)
    - Leslie, A. M., 1982 (Box-folder 128: 11)
    - Mont Pèlerin Society (Carl-Johan Westholm), 1991 (Box-folder 128: 12)
    - Morris, Walter S., 1983-1991 (Box-folder 128: 13)
    - Oddenyo, John F. E., 1992 (Box-folder 128: 14)
    - Oehler, Ellen, 1977 (Box-folder 128: 15)
    - Opton, Gene, 1990 (Box-folder 128: 16)
    - Shafarevich, I. R., 2000 (Box-folder 128: 17)
    - Vaughn, Karen I., 1985 (Box-folder 128: 18)
  - Speeches and Writings III, 1926-1999
    Articles, monographs, and speeches, arranged chronologically.
    - "Francis Ysidro Edgeworth,", 1926 (Box-folder 128: 19)
    - "Neuere Literatur über amerikanisches Bankwesen,", 1926 (Box-folder 128: 20)
    - "Friedrich Wieser,", 1926 July 6 (Box-folder 128: 21)
    - Summary of proceedings, Conference of Economic Services, London, England, 1928 June 26-28 (Box-folder 128: 22)
    - Review of Jules Dupuit, De l'utilité et de sa mesure, published in The Economist Monthly Book Supplement, 1933 June 9 (Box-folder 128: 23)
    - "Philippovich von Philippsberg, Eugen," Encyclopaedia of the Social Sciences, 1933 (Box-folder 128: 24)
    - "Mr. Keynes' Scheme of Compulsory Saving,", 1939-1940 (Box-folder 128: 25)
    - "Die wirtschaftlichen Voraussetzungen für einen Staatenbund,", 1939 (Box-folder 128: 26)
    - "Abuse and Decline of Reason,", 1939 (Box-folder 128: 27)
    - Introduction to Henry Thornton, An Enquiry into the Nature and Effects of the Paper Credit, 1939 (Box-folder 128: 28)
    - "J. S. Mill, Mrs. Taylor, and Socialism,", 1940 (Box-folder 128: 29)
    - "An English Speaking College of Social Studies for Central Europe,", 1943 February 12 (Box-folder 128: 30)
    - "The Dispersal of the Books and Papers of John Stuart Mill,", 1944 February 7 (Box-folder 128: 31)
    - "J. S. Mill's Correspondence,", 1943 February 13 (Box-folder 128: 32)
    - "Report on Some Economic Problems of Gibraltar,", 1944 October (Box-folder 128: 33)
    - "What Is Mind?", 1945-1948
      - First draft, 1945 (Box-folder 128: 34)
      - Second draft, 1947 (Box-folder 128: 35)
      - Third draft, 1948
        - Chapters 1-4 (Box-folder 129: 1)
        - Chapters 5-7 (Box-folder 129: 2)
    - Appeal on behalf of Austrian scholars, 1948 (Box-folder 129: 3)
    - Review of Beatrice Webb, Our Partnership and Edgar Reichel, Der Sozialismus der Fabier, 1948 (Box-folder 129: 4)
    - "A Grammar of the Economic Calculus,", 1952
      - Notes, 1952 (Box-folder 129: 5)
      - Draft, 1952 (Box-folder 129: 6)
    - "Within Systems and About Systems,", 1952 (Box-folder 129: 7)
    - "Memorandum on Conditions and Needs of the University of Vienna,", 1955-1956 (Box-folder 129: 8)
    - "Memorandum on Plan for Work,", 1959 November (Box-folder 129: 9)
    - "Valedictory," circular sent to members of the Mont Pèlerin Society, 1962 February (Box-folder 129: 10)
    - Introduction to Frédéric Bastiat, Essays on Political Economy, 1964 (Box-folder 129: 11)
    - Preface to the Italian edition of Studies in Philosophy, Politics and Economics, 1966 (Box-folder 129: 12)
    - Talk on the history of economic theory, 1970 (Box-folder 129: 13)
    - "An Analysis of the Productive Nature of Money,", 1973 (Box-folder 129: 14)
    - Law, Legislation and Liberty: A New Statement of the Liberal Principles of Justice and Political Economy. Volume 1, Rules and Order, 1973 (Box-folder 129: 15)
      Draft of chapters 9-10.
    - "Inflation and Unemployment,", 1974 (Box-folder 129: 16)
    - Preface to the French edition of Prices and Production, 1975 (Box-folder 129: 17)
    - Preface to the Japanese edition of selected works by Hayek, 1975 (Box-folder 129: 18)
    - "International Money," address, Geneva Gold and Monetary Conference, Lausanne, Switzerland, 1975 September 25 (Box-folder 129: 19)
    - Introduction to Ludwig von Mises, Kritik des Interventionismus, 1976 (Box-folder 129: 20)
    - Introduction to the German edition of Robert Nozick, Anarchy, State, and Utopia, 1976 (Box-folder 129: 21)
    - Law, Legislation and Liberty: A New Statement of the Liberal Principles of Justice and Political Economy. Volume 2, The Mirage of Social Justice, fragment and footnotes, 1976 (Box-folder 129: 22)
    - "The Passionate Philosopher,", 1976 (Box-folder 129: 23)
    - Speech on socialism, 1976 (Box-folder 130: 1)
    - "The Illusion of Social Justice,", 1977 (Box-folder 130: 2)
    - Preface to New Studies in Philosophy, Poltics, Economics and the History of Ideas, 1977 (Box-folder 130: 3)
    - "The Destruction of Classical Liberalism by Legal Positivism,", 1978 (Box-folder 130: 4)
    - "The Miscarriage of the Democratic Ideal,", 1978 (Box-folder 130: 5)
    - Letter to the editor, The Times (London), 1978 February 11 (Box-folder 130: 6)
    - Letter to the editor, The Times (London), 1978 March 1 (Box-folder 130: 7)
    - Introduction to Ludwig von Mises, Socialism, 1978 August (Box-folder 130: 8)
    - "Exploitation of Workers by Workers," The Listener, 1978 August 17 (Box-folder 130: 9)
    - "The Reactionary Character of the Socialist Conception," talk, Hoover Institution, Stanford University, Stanford, California, 1978 October 27 (Box-folder 130: 10)
    - Law, Legislation and Liberty: A New Statement of the Liberal Principles of Justice and Political Economy. Volume 3, The Political Order of a Free People, 1979 (Box-folder 130: 11)
    - Recht, Gesetz und Freiheit, 1979 (Box-folder 130: 12-14)
    - Unemployment and Monetary Policy, 1979 (Box-folder 130: 15)
    - "Zur Neuausgabe der Werke Wilhelm Röpkes,", 1979 (Box-folder 130: 16)
    - "Wissenschaft und Sozialismus," address, University of Freiburg University, Freiburg im Breisgau, Germany, 1979 February 6 (Box-folder 130: 17)
      Includes English version, "Science and Socialism."
    - "Vote of Thanks,", 1979 May 10 (Box-folder 130: 18)
    - Introduction to Ewald Schams, Gesammelte Aufsätze, 1980 (Box-folder 130: 19)
    - "Friedrich Hayek on the Crisis," interview, 1980 January (Box-folder 130: 20)
    - Letter to the editor, The Times (London), 1980 January 1 (Box-folder 130: 21)
    - Letter to the editor, The Times (London), 1980 March 5 (Box-folder 130: 22)
    - "The Muddle of the Middle," lecture, Monday Club, London, England, 1980 March 26 (Box-folder 131: 1)
    - Letter to the editor, The Times (London), 1980 June 13 (Box-folder 131: 2)
    - "Austrian School,", 1981 (Box-folder 131: 3)
    - "The Flow of Goods and Services," lecture, London School of Economics, 1981 January 27 (Box-folder 131: 4)
    - "The Future Unit of Value," address, Visa International Annual Conference, Athens, Greece, 1981 September 14 (Box-folder 131: 5)
    - "Employment and Inflation,", 1982 (Box-folder 131: 6)
    - "Private and Public Aims," J. B. Morrell Memorial Address on Toleration, University of York, Heslington, England, 1982 March 12 (Box-folder 131: 7)
    - "Keynes and Inflation,", 1983 (Box-folder 131: 8)
    - "Die Wiederentdeckung der Freiheit - persönliche Erinnerungen," speech, 1983 February 2 (Box-folder 131: 9)
    - "J. M. Keynes, 1928-1946," (Box-folder 131: 10)
    - Talk between Hayek and Christian Seidl, University of Freiburg, Freiburg im Breisgau, Germany, 1983 September 28 (Box-folder 131: 11)
    - Introduction to Money, Capital and Fluctuations, 1984 (Box-folder 131: 12)
    - "Harold Laski's Opinions,", 1984 April (Box-folder 131: 13)
    - "Current Demand and Current Employment,", 1984 October 2 (Box-folder 131: 14)
    - "The Presumption of Reason,", 1985 (Box-folder 131: 15)
    - "The Standard,", 1985 (Box-folder 131: 16)
    - "The Case for 'The Standard'," talk, Institute of Economic Affairs, London, England, 1985 July 5 (Box-folder 131: 17)
    - Central Planning, pamphlet adapted from The Fatal Conceit, 1988 (Box-folder 131: 18)
    - The Fatal Conceit, published, 1988
      - Notes, undated (Box-folder 131: 19)
      - Draft, 1985 (Box-folder 131: 20-21)
      - Other drafts, 1981-1986
        - Preface, undated (Box-folder 132: 1)
        - Table of contents, undated (Box-folder 132: 2)
        - Introduction, undated (Box-folder 132: 3-6)
        - Chapter one, 1981-1986
          - undated (Box-folder 132: 4-16)
          - German version, undated (Box-folder 132: 17)
          - 1983 (Box-folder 132: 18-19)
          - 1986 (Box-folder 132: 20)
        - Chapter two headings, undated (Box-folder 132: 21)
        - Chapter two, undated (Box-folder 132: 22-26)
        - Chapter two, undated (Box-folder 133: 1-3)
        - Chapter three, undated (Box-folder 133: 4-7)
        - Chapter four, undated (Box-folder 133: 8-12)
        - Chapter five, 1981
          - undated (Box-folder 133: 13-16)
          - 1981 (Box-folder 133: 17)
        - Chapter six, 1985
          - undated (Box-folder 133: 18-19)
          - 1985 May (Box-folder 133: 20)
          - 1985 June (Box-folder 133: 21)
        - Chapter seven, 1984
          - undated (Box-folder 134: 1-4)
          - 1984 (Box-folder 134: 5)
        - Introduction to part two, undated (Box-folder 134: 6)
        - Chapter eight, undated (Box-folder 134: 7)
        - Chapter nine, undated (Box-folder 134: 8-9)
        - Chapter ten, undated (Box-folder 134: 10-12)
        - Chapter eleven, undated (Box-folder 134: 13)
        - Chapter twelve, undated (Box-folder 134: 14)
        - Chapter thirteen, undated (Box-folder 134: 15-16)
        - Chapter fourteen, undated (Box-folder 134: 17-18)
        - Chapter fifteen, undated
        - Chapter sixteen, undated (Box-folder 134: 21)
        - Chapter seventeen, undated (Box-folder 134: 22-23)
        - Chapter eighteen, undated (Box-folder 134: 24-25)
        - Chapter nineteen, undated (Box-folder 134: 26)
        - Chapter twenty, undated (Box-folder 134: 27)
        - Chapter twenty one, undated (Box-folder 134: 28)
        - Conclusion, undated (Box-folder 134: 29)
    - "Dr. Bernard Mandeville," Commentaire, 1999 Spring (Box-folder 134: 30)
  - Reviews of Works By and About Hayek, 1929-1985
    Articles and comments, arranged chronologically.
    - Geldtheorie und Konjunkturtheorie, 1929-1930 (Box-folder 135: 1)
    - Das Mieterschutzproblem, 1930 (Box-folder 135: 2)
    - Beiträge zur Geldtheorie, 1933 (Box-folder 135: 3)
    - Monetary Theory and the Trade Cycle, 1933 (Box-folder 135: 4)
    - Collectivist Economic Planning, 1935 (Box-folder 135: 5)
    - Monetary Nationalism and International Stability, 1937 (Box-folder 135: 6)
    - Profits, Interest and Investment, 1939 (Box-folder 135: 7)
    - The Pure Theory of Capital, 1941 (Box-folder 135: 8)
    - Introductory essay, John Stuart Mill, Spirit of the Age, 1942 (Box-folder 135: 9)
    - The Road to Serfdom, 1944-1985
      - 1944 (Box-folder 135: 10-14)
      - 1944-1945 (Box-folder 135: 15)
      - 1945 (Box-folder 136: 1-5)
      - 1946 (Box-folder 136: 6)
      - 1947-1956 (Box-folder 136: 7)
      - 1958 (Box-folder 136: 8)
      - 1970-1985 (Box-folder 136: 9)
    - Individualism: True and False, 1946 (Box-folder 137: 1)
    - Individualism and Economic Order, 1948-1949 (Box-folder 137: 2)
    - "Intellectuals and Socialism," commentaries from initial readers, 1948-1949 (Box-folder 137: 3)
    - John Stuart Mill and Harriet Taylor, 1951-1952
      - 1951 (Box-folder 137: 4)
      - 1951-1952 (Box-folder 137: 5)
    - The Counter-Revolution of Science, 1952-1953 (Box-folder 137: 6)
    - Individualismus und wirtschaftliche Ordnung, 1952-1953 (Box-folder 137: 7)
    - The Sensory Order, 1952-1953 (Box-folder 137: 8)
    - Capitalism and the Historians, 1954-1959 (Box-folder 137: 9)
    - "Degrees of Explanation," comments, 1955 (Box-folder 137: 10)
    - Mißbrauch und Verfall der Vernunft, 1959-1961 (Box-folder 137: 11)
    - Studies in Philosophy, Politics and Economics, 1967-1968 (Box-folder 137: 12)
    - A Tiger by the Tail, 1971-1972 (Box-folder 137: 13)
    - Full Employment at Any Price?, 1975 (Box-folder 137: 14)
    - Denationalization of Money, 1976-1977 (Box-folder 137: 15)
    - Books about Hayek, 1976-1985 (Box-folder 137: 16)